(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
湊あくあ / 常闇トワ
Minato Aqua / Tokoyami Towa
兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン
Usada Pekora / Houshou Marine
白上フブキ / 戌神ころね / 猫又おかゆ
Shirakami Fubuki / Inugami Korone / Nekomata Okayu
がうる・ぐら / 森カリオペ
Gawr Gura / Mori Calliope
止まらない
I can't stop
恋の罠に
Falling for the trap of love
虜ね 夢中に
I'm a prisoner, obsessed with you
よそ見ダーリン
Looking away, darling
ダメダメよ
That's a no-no
痛いの飛んでけ
Pain, pain, go away
残るのは愛だけ
All that's left is love
キュンと
My heart skips a beat
私の
For my
恋心
Pure love
一人だけ嫌い
I hate being alone
触れるだけで
Just by a simple touch
つながる予感
I feel a connection coming
好きな感情
These feelings of love
周りの目なんて
I don't care what others think
関係ない
It doesn't matter
いわゆるあの
It's what they call
盲目なのお
Being blind with love
最高なファッション
With the best fashion sense
センス 私になれない
That I could never match
羨ましい
It's enviable
悲しいこの話
What a sad story this is
メンションで
Feelings conveyed
伝える気持ち
Through mentions
ほら言葉で
Come on, I want you to
伝えてほしいの
Tell me with words
止まらない
I can't stop
恋心の
This love's
罠に
Trap
虜ね 夢中に
I'm a prisoner, obsessed with you
よそ見ダーリン
Looking away, darling
ダメダメよ
That's a no-no
痛いの飛んでけ
Pain, pain, go away
残るの愛だけ
All that's left is love
これも辛いけど
Even if this is painful
騙して
Deceive me
夢
A dream
夢に溺れ
Drown me in a dream
もう等身大の
There's no more
愛はないよ
True-to-life love
恋の罠に
Falling for the trap of love
虜ね 夢中に
I'm a prisoner, obsessed with you
キュンと
My heart skips a beat
私の
For my
恋心
Pure love
私は地雷
I'm a landmine
指をさされ
Pointed at by fingers
触れると危険
Dangerous to touch
恋は惨事
Love is a disaster
あなたは今
Right now, you...
誰のために
...for whose sake...
愛を語る
...are you speaking of love?
私でしょう？
It's me, isn't it?
天才なファッションセンス
A genius fashion sense
大人じゃ無理よ
Adults can't handle it
エナドリにストロー
Straws in energy drinks
つけたリボン
And attached ribbons
ナンセンス外野のメロディー
The nonsense melody of the bystanders
その心は心臓から
That feeling, from the bottom of my heart...
ロッカガチュウ
Rock-a-chu
縛りたいな
I want to tie you down
お互いに
Mutually
ハズさないと不安に
Feeling anxious if we aren't connected
形にしなきゃ
I have to make it tangible
ダメダメよ
Or it's no good
二人は従順に
We are both obedient
若さは牢獄に
Youth is a prison
乙女度倍で行こう
Let's double our maidenly spirit
満たして
Fill me up
辛い辛いの世界
In this painful, painful world
もう何千回と耐えた夜へ
Into the night I've endured thousands of times
愛はお互いに分からず夢中に
Captivated by a love we both don't understand
きっと涙のアイワナムチュー
Surely, a tearful I-Wanna-Muchu
愛されたいけど
I want to be loved, but...
愛したいのよ
...I want to love you
やっぱりどうしても愛されたいよ
After all, I really do want to be loved
人ってそういうもんじゃないの？
Isn't that just how people are?
曖昧ミーマイン
Ambiguous Me-Mine
やっぱりね
I knew it
地固中 上等でしょう
Securing my ground, it's great, right?
絶叫はノー！
No screaming!
止まらない恋の罠に虜で夢中に
Captivated by the trap of an unstoppable love
よそ見ダーリン
Don't look away, darling
ダメダメよ
It's no good
痛いの飛んでけ
Pain, pain, go away
残るのは愛だけ
Only love remains
これも辛いけど
This is painful too, but...
騙して
Deceive me
夢 夢に溺れ
Drowning in a dream
もう等身大の愛はないよ
There's no longer a life-sized love
恋の罠に虜で夢中に
Captivated by the trap of love
キュンと私の恋心
My heart skips a beat for love
ララララ 病的アイニージュー
La-la-la-la, pathological I-need-you
ララララ 孤独は病
La-la-la-la, loneliness is a sickness
ララララ 盲目アイニージュー
La-la-la-la, blind I-need-you
ずっと
Always
あなたに
...for you...
アイワナムチュー
I-Wanna-Muchu
思い出すのは
What I remember is...
君の歌
...your song
会話よりも
More than conversation...
鮮明だ
...it's vivid
どこに
Where...
行ってしまったの
...have you gone?
いつも探すんだよ
I'm always searching for you
思い出すのは
What I remember is...
君の歌
...your song
歌う笑う顔が
Your singing, laughing face...
鮮明だ
...is vivid
君に似合うんだよ
It suits you well
ずっと見ていたいよ
I want to keep watching you forever
でも最後に
But at the end...
見たいのは
...what I want to see...
きっともう
...is surely...
君の夢の中
...already inside your dream
もう一度
One more time...
また聴かせてくれよ
...let me hear it again
聴きたいんだ
I want to hear it
もっと騒げ 怪獣の歌
Make more noise, the monster's song
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 口ずさんで
It hasn't faded yet, I end up humming it
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 口ずさんでしまうよ
It hasn't faded yet, I end up humming it
思い出すのは
What I remember is...
君が弾いた ギターモデル
...the guitar model you played
君がいた
You were there
忘れられないんだよ
I can't forget you
だから僕が歌うよ
So I'm going to sing
でも最後に
But at the end...
見たいのは
...what I want to see...
きっともう
...is surely...
君の夢の中
...already inside your dream
もう一度
One more time...
また聴かせてくれよ
...let me hear it again
聴きたいんだ
I want to hear it
もっと騒げ 怪獣の歌
Make more noise, the monster's song
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 口ずさんで
It hasn't faded yet, I end up humming it
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 口ずさんでしまうよ
It hasn't faded yet, I end up humming it
落ちていく
Falling away...
過去は鮮明で
...the past is vivid
見せたい
The future...
未来は繊細だ
...I want to show you is delicate
過ぎていく 日々には鈍感な
Passing through days, insensitive...
君へ
...to you
落ちていく
Falling away...
過去は鮮明で
...the past is vivid
見せたい
The future...
未来は繊細だ
...I want to show you is delicate
過ぎていく 日々には鈍感な
Passing through days, insensitive...
君へ
...to you
ねえ
Hey...
もっと騒げ 怪獣の歌
Make more noise, the monster's song
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 夢の歌唱えて
Sing the dream song that hasn't faded yet
君がいつも 歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない 口ずさんでしまうよ
It hasn't faded yet, I end up humming it
ねえ
Hey...
僕ら 眠れない夜に
...we, during sleepless nights...
手を伸ばして
...reach out our hands
眠れない夜も
Sleepless nights, too...
また伸ばして
...reach out again
手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand
眠れない夜をまた伸ばして
Extending the sleepless night again
眠くない今だね
I'm still not sleepy
そんな日々でいたいのにね
Even though I want to stay in those days
眠れない夜に手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand in the sleepless night
眠れない夜をまた伸ばして
Extending the sleepless night again
眠くない今だね
I'm still not sleepy
そんな夜に歌う
Singing on such a night
怪獣の歌
The monster's song
Monster's Song
過ぎていく日々はどうかな
How are the days passing by?
落ちていく
Falling down
過去は冴えないね
The past is dull
見せたい未来は繊細で
The future I want to show is delicate
過ぎていく日々はどうかな
How are the days passing by?
君がね
You...
ミカヅキ
Crescent Moon
今宵満月ではないわ
It's not a full moon tonight
嫌いな満月がキラキラ
The hated full moon is sparkling
幸せそうに世界を照らしている
Happily lighting up the world
丁度私はできそこないでどうしようもなくて
Exactly, I'm a failure and there's nothing I can do
夜明け夢見ては地べた這いずり回ってる
Dreaming of dawn, crawling around on the ground
それでも誰かに見つけて欲しくて
Still, I want someone to find me
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Looking up at the night sky and screaming
逃げ出したい 逃げ出せない
I want to escape, I can't escape
明るい未来は見えないね
I can't see a bright future, can I?
それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて
Still, I want you to find me
蝶のように舞い上がるの
I'll soar like a butterfly
欠けた翼で飛んだ
I flew with broken wings
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
The ugly star-child, Mikazuki
今宵満月ではないわ
It's not a full moon tonight
嫌いな満月がユラユラ
The hated full moon is swaying
誰かの腕に抱かれて眠っている
Sleeping in someone's arms
丁度私は一人の夜に押しつぶされては
Exactly, I'm being crushed by a lonely night
誰にも見えない夜闇這いずり回ってる
Crawling around in the darkness that no one can see
それでも誰にも負けたくなくて
Still, I don't want to lose to anyone
宇宙の隅でもがいている
Struggling in a corner of the universe
追いつきたい 追い越したい
I want to catch up, I want to overtake
夢に見たいような世界ね
A world like one I'd see in a dream, right?
それとも誰かと比べてばかり
Still, always comparing myself to someone
周りを見ては立ち止まって
Looking around and stopping
欠けたものを探した
Searching for what's missing
そんな自分を変えたい
I want to change that self
それでもあなたと同じ景色がまた見たいから
Because I still want to see the same scenery as you again
泣き出したくても 投げ出したくても
Even if I want to cry, even if I want to give up
諦めたりはできない
I can't give up
それでもあなたに見つかるように
Still, so that you can find me
蛹は強く手を伸ばすの
The chrysalis strongly reaches out its hand
欠けたもの抱きしめて
Embracing the missing pieces
願いを放つよ ミカヅキ
I'll release my wish, Mikazuki
それでも誰かに見つけて欲しくて
Still, I want someone to find me
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Looking up at the night sky and screaming
泣き出したいけど 泣き出さない
I want to cry, but I won't cry
もう後戻りなどできないね
I can't turn back anymore, can I?
それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて
Still, I want you to find me
蝶のように舞い上がるの
I'll soar like a butterfly
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ
I'll fly with broken wings
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
The ugly star-child, Mikazuki
光を放った ミカヅキ
Released the light, Mikazuki
ミカヅキ
Mikazuki
いつかは君のままだと
Sometime, as you are
笑っている
smiling.
はーい！
Hi!
I wanna be、かいじゅうの花唄、ミカヅキでしたー！
That was "I wanna be," "Kaijuu no Hanauta," and "Mikazuki"!
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな見てるー？ちゃんと見てたー？
Is everyone watching? Were you watching closely?
3曲ね、連続で最初から歌っちゃいましたけど、どうでしたか？
I sang three songs in a row right from the start. How was it?
可愛かった？
Was I cute?
ま、きっと可愛かったでしょう。えへへ。
Well, I'm sure I was. Ehehe.
ねぇ見て、ステージすごくない？見て、これ。
Hey, look, isn't the stage amazing? Look at this.
すごいでしょ！超可愛いよ。
Isn't it great! It's super cute.
ほら、上とかさ、お月様があって...
Look, up there's the moon...
塩っ子もいて、あ、カメラマンやってくれてるんだよね、上に3人。
And there are Shiokko. Oh, they're acting as cameramen, the three up there.
見て、見えるかな？
Look, can you see them?
あいつ、あいつら。
Those guys, right there.
あ、照明らしい。ははは。
Oh, apparently they're lighting. Hahaha.
照明らしい。かわ、え、可愛い。めっちゃ可愛いじゃん。
Apparently lighting. Cu- wait, cute. They're so cute.
そう、超可愛いんだよ。塩っ子もね、帽子被ってて、めっちゃ可愛いんだ。
Yeah, they're super cute. The Shiokko are wearing hats, they're so cute.
こっち、ここにもいるけど。
There's one over here too.
これ何持ってんだろね？
I wonder what they're holding?
うまい棒みたいなの持ってる。
They're holding something that looks like Umaibou.
でね、でね、見て見て。こっち！
And, and, look, look. Over here!
ほら見て！こいつ超可愛い！見て！
Look at this! This guy is super cute! Look!
いぇーい！
Yay!
あ、いいじゃんこれ。写真撮ってください！
Ah, this is great. Please take a photo!
え、可愛いでしょ！
Isn't it cute!
これはね、メイド衣装のここについてるあの、ぬいぐるみだね。
This is the plushie that's attached to my maid outfit.
目玉の、目玉がボタンのぬいぐるみね。
The plushie with buttons for eyes.
いや超可愛いんだよ。下はね、魔法陣になってんだよね。
It's so cute. And the floor is a magic circle.
いや可愛すぎる本当に。めっちゃピンクと紫で超可愛い。
It's really too cute. All the pink and purple is super cute.
ということで、新しいステージでした。
So, this was the new stage.
可愛いでしょ！めっちゃシオンっぽくて超可愛いよね。
It's cute, right! It's so Shion-like and super cute.
であとね、後ろの絵！
And also, the picture in the back!
これが今回のサムネ의 イラストなんだけど、あれ？
This is the illustration for this time's thumbnail, but... wait?
なんか、周りにね、いっぱいいてね... これね...
There's, like, a lot of people around... And this...
誰だろう？
I wonder who they are?
え、誰だろう誰だろう。え、もしかして出てくるのかな？この先。
I wonder who, I wonder who. Could it be they'll show up later on?
え、どうなんだろう。いや分かんないな、分かんないんだけど、かも知れないよね。
Well, I wonder. I don't know, I don't know, but it might be.
かも知れないんだよね。イラスト超可愛いっしょ、これ。サムネなんだけどね。
It might be. The illustration is super cute, right? It's the thumbnail.
ということで、なんと気づけばもう5年も経ってしまっていました。
So, before I knew it, five years had already passed.
怖すぎる。
It's too scary.
まだ気分は新人バーチャルYouTuberなのに！
Even though I still feel like a rookie Virtual YouTuber!
怖すぎるよ！はぁー。
Too scary! Haa.
5年目も頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best in my fifth year too!
ということで、あ、ハッシュタグは紫咲シオン5周年記念で、
And also, the hashtag is #紫咲シオン5周年記念,
みんなたくさん可愛い写真撮ってツイートしてください。後で見るよ。
so please take lots of cute photos and tweet them. I'll check them later.
はい、というわけで、ここからはゲストパートです！
Alright, and with that, from here on is the guest part!
最後までたっぷりあるので、ぜひ見てってください。
There's plenty more until the end, so please keep watching.
最後まで見てね！
Watch until the very end!
頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best!
劣等上等
Inferiority Superiority / Bring It On
Yeah!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等 Bring it on
Inferiority Superiority, bring it on!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等 in Japan
Inferiority Superiority in Japan!
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Child's play Mathematica,
バレてんだってそんなんじゃプライドがない
it's obvious, you have no pride like that.
媚びへつらい上機嫌で
Flattering others in high spirits,
他人の見物ばかりじゃつまんねぇ
just watching others is boring.
ほらもっと
Look, more,
間違って
make mistakes,
ちょっと
just a bit,
退屈に手をかけて
give a hand to the boredom.
ママ、やっぱ私は
Mama, as I thought, I...
こんなところじゃ終われない
...can't end in a place like this.
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm going crazy,
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
goodbye to playing pretend and acting.
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Staying like this forever is...
いられない
...something I can't do.
ダッ ダッ ダッ 私大人になる
Da, da, da, I'm going to grow up.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Having tasted both the bitter and the sweet, now,
パッ パッ パッ 変わる時代
pa, pa, pa, the era changes.
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not all bad things, right?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
Past, sins, punishment, everything,
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり返すわ
I'll survive with my bare hands and love, and I'll strike back.
Yeah! 注目！あたしたちはナンバーワン
Yeah! Attention! We are number one!
さあ、バー、いつになったら貰える合格
Come on, bar, when will I get a passing grade?
赤ペン入れてよ どっかダメなんですか？
Put a red pen in, what's wrong with it?
酒 お金 ドラック やっちゃんてコンプラ
Alcohol, money, drugs, doing them all, compliance
知るかよオーライ 上等じゃブラッジョ
Who cares, alright? It's fine, bravo!
中指立てたくなるような現状 ありすぎて指が足りねえから変座
Current situation makes me want to flip the bird, too many things, not enough fingers, so sit down!
本末転倒 モボモガ モガいて
Putting the cart before the horse, modern boys and girls struggling
ままならねえな 欲しがります死ぬまでは
Nothing goes as planned, I'll keep wanting it until I die
伸びた背丈そうだ 街に投げキス
Look at how tall I've grown, blowing a kiss to the city
見せ場はここから 覚悟しとけよ
The main attraction starts here, so you better be ready
ダッ ダッ ダッ 僕ら大人になる
Da da da, we become adults
カウンター狙い
Aiming for a counter
最低な日々に
In these terrible days
腕っ節とかます一撃
Delivering a blow with physical strength
誰も読めない先 まだあいこでしょ
An unreadable future, it's still a tie, right?
バグも、
Bugs,
ノイズも、
Noise,
ズレも、
Deviations,
すべて
Everything
素手で、
With bare hands,
生きて！
Live!
生き抜いて覆すよ
Survive and overturn it
だってくだらない
Because it's only trivial
ことばっか 揺るがない
Things, but I'm unshakeable
わかるか 私の美学が
Do you understand my aesthetics?
この馬鹿正直な
This foolishly honest
拳一つが 打ち出す手札
Single fist is the card I play
愚直なんです 喰らえよ
I'm just straightforward, take this!
ズバッと 一抜け さあ
Straight through, first one out, come on!
Oh oh oh...
こんなもんじゃない
It's not just this
ダッ ダッ ダッ あたし大人になる
Da da da, I become an adult
酸いも甘いも 噛み分けて今
Tasting both the sour and the sweet now
燦々 交わるミライ
Brilliantly intersecting future
もう子供じゃないの わかるでしょ
I'm not a child anymore, you understand, right?
時代 機会 待ってくれない
Era, opportunity, they won't wait
素手で、捨て身で、生き抜いて
With bare hands, desperately, survive
上等だわ
Bring it on
愛ある時代
An era with love
それでは皆様、お先にバイバイ
Well then everyone, goodbye for now
フロアが 湧き上がりました
The floor has heated up!
さあ 眠眠打破 昼夜逆転
Come on, caffeine intake, day and night reversal
VOX AC30w
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンドの仲間に「ヤッホー」
A subculture boy with a Telecaster says "Yahoo" to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード 対バンには人見知り
Part-time job is in dark mode, shy at the joint gig
宣言通り逃げる ギガボーイ
Fleeing as declared, Giga Boy
よだれ垂らしてお金も才能も 生真面目があるだけ厄介でしょ
Drooling, money, talent, just being serious is a nuisance, right?
Boys be ambitious like this old man
長い前髪 君は誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者
Follower
勘違いすんな 教祖はオマエだ
Don't get it wrong, the cult leader is you
ロキロキのロックンロール かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
Roki Roki's Rock 'n' Roll, the electric guitar being strummed is...
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ君の全てを 曝け出してみせろよ
Come on, show me everything you've got
ロキロキのロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock 'n' Roll
さあ 日進月歩 いい曲書いてる？
Come on, steady progress, are you writing good songs?
知名度はあるけど人気はそんなにないから色々大変ですね
You're known but not that popular, so things are tough, aren't they?
はっきり言うなよ匿名アイコン
Don't say it so clearly, anonymous icon
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Don't show it so clearly, real-life photo icon
いとおしくなって 自意識マッドボーイ
Becoming lovely, self-conscious mad boy
ぶっちゃけ どんだけ 賢く あざとく やったって 十年後には メイクは落ちてんだよ
To be honest, no matter how craftily you do it, ten years later, the makeup will be gone
Boys be ambitious like this old man
生き抜くためだ キメろよ自撮り
It's for survival, take that selfie
Selfy
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな
Don't die, both of us
ロキロキのロックンロール 薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい
Roki Roki's Rock 'n' Roll, even a shallow love song is fine
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Come on, shoot through that girl in front of you
ロキロキのロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock 'n' Roll
…して満足できない
...and still not satisfied.
素敵に憧れたステロイド 言葉は…
Steroids I admired so beautifully, the words are...
安心不安心 プレッシャーで一杯
Relief and anxiety, I'm full of pressure.
実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません
Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and lost my voice.
はっ！
Ha!
寝言は寝て言え Baby
Save the sleep-talking for when you're asleep, Baby.
Baby Baby Baby Baby Baby Baby
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you go and die!
お互いにな！
Same to you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll.
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
The strumming electric guitar goes Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ君の全てを 曝け出してみせろよ
Now, show me everything you've got.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll.
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you go and die!
死にたかねえのは お互い様！
Neither of us wants to die, we're in the same boat!
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love...
幸せの空
...under a sky of happiness.
隣どおし あなたと
Side by side, with you...
あたし さくらんぼ
...and me, we're cherries.
手帳を開くともう
When I open my planner, I see...
2年たつなぁって
...it's already been two years.
四六時中一緒だね
We're together 24/7, aren't we?
何だか照れたりするね
It's kind of embarrassing, somehow.
そういやひどいこともされたし
Come to think of it, you've been mean to me...
ひどいことも言ったし
...and I've said mean things to you too.
中身がいっぱい詰まった
But it's filled to the brim...
甘い甘いものです
...with sweet, sweet things.
泣きな晴れた1日
A day that started with tears but cleared up,
自転車の旅や
our bicycle trip and all...
書きあらわせない
I can't even write it all down,
だって多いんだもん
because there's just so much.
笑顔咲く 君と
With a blooming smile, with you...
つながってたい
...I want to stay connected.
もしあの向こうに
If beyond that horizon,
見えるものがあるなら
there's something to be seen...
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love...
幸せの空
...under a sky of happiness.
隣どおし あなたと
Side by side, with you...
あたし さくらんぼ
...and me, we're cherries.
もらったものはそう
What I received, yes,
愛を感じ
I felt the love.
あげたものはもちろん
And what I gave was, of course,
全力の愛です
love with all my might.
やっぱりねー
Just as I thought,
共同作業です
it's a joint effort.
思いがけなく歴史は
History unexpectedly
さらに深くなるけど
will only grow deeper.
ひとつでも欠けてたら
If even one piece were missing,
とんでもなく足りない
it would be terribly incomplete.
2人の絆
The bond between the two of us.
笑顔咲く 君と
With a blooming smile, with you...
抱き合ってたい
...I want to be holding you.
もし遠い未来を
If we were to predict
予想するのなら
the distant future...
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love,
いつ時の時も
at all times.
隣どおし あなたと
Side by side, with you...
あたし さくらんぼ
...and me, we're cherries.
笑顔咲く 君と
With a blooming smile, with you...
つながってたい
...I want to stay connected.
もしあの向こうに
If beyond that horizon,
見えるものがあるなら
there's something to be seen...
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love...
幸せの空
...under a sky of happiness.
隣どおし あなたと
Side by side, with you...
あたし さくらんぼ
...and me, we're cherries.
もういっかい！
One more time!
笑顔咲く 君と
With a blooming smile, with you...
抱き合ってたい
...I want to be holding you.
もし遠い未来を
If we were to predict
予想するのなら
the distant future...
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love,
いつ時の時も
at all times.
隣どおし あなたと
Side by side, with you...
あたし さくらんぼ
...and me, we're cherries.
愛し合う ２人
Two people in love...
いつ時の時も
...at all times.
Yeah! Un!
Yeah! Mm!
愛し合う
Loving each other
二人
Two of us
いつまでも
Forever
一緒
Together
隣どおし
Side by side
あなたと
With you
あたし
And me
さくらんぼ
Cherry
ぱっとぱっと
Suddenly, suddenly
晴れやかに
Cheerfully
咲かせましょう
Let's make it bloom
花のように
Like a flower
欲しいのは
What I want
少しの
Is a little bit of
踏み出す力と
Courage to step forward
弱気な
Opening up
心を
My timid
開ける魔法の鍵
Heart with a magic key
それでもいい
Even so, it's fine
踏み
Step
勢いよく跳ねて
Leap forward with vigor
始まる夢は
The dream that begins...
夢は
...the dream
どんな形？
What kind of shape?
踊れや踊れ
Dance and dance
散らさないで
Don't let them scatter
もっともっと
More and more
一緒に
Together
数えたい
I want to count
新しい景色
The new scenery
いろはにほっ
Iroha ni ho-
ぱっとぱっと
Suddenly, suddenly
晴れやかに
Cheerfully
咲かせましょう
Let's make it bloom
花のように
Like a flower
これからも
From now on
君が
I want to
見たい
See you
いろはにほっ
Iroha ni ho-
ぱっとぱっと
Suddenly, suddenly
晴れやかに
Cheerfully
咲かせる思いは
The feelings blooming are
常ならば
If it's always like this
だって
Because
乙女心は
A maiden's heart
風まかせだと
Is left to the wind
呟いてみた
I tried murmuring
乙女心さ
It's a maiden's heart
迷ってる
If I'm just
だけなら
Wandering about
何も起こらない
Nothing will happen
強気で
I'll say
行くんだと
"I'm going with strength!"
瞳で語るよ
My eyes tell the story
そしたらさ
And then
おいで
Come here
明日がピカピカと
Tomorrow will shine brightly
輝く夢の
Of the shining dream...
夢の
...of the dream
色に変わる
Changing into colors
歌えや歌え
Sing and sing
浮かれながら
While being festive
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever
一緒に
Together
遊びたい
I want to play
桜色ハーモニー
Cherry blossom colored harmony
ちりぬるを
Chirinuru o
さっとさっと
Quickly, quickly
流れてく
It flows by
うたかたの
Transient
花の香り
Scent of flowers
いつまでも
Forever
君と
I want to
いたい
Be with you
ちりぬるを
Chirinuru o
さっとさっと
Quickly, quickly
流れてく
It flows by
出会いと別れに
In meetings and partings
酔いもせず
Without getting drunk
そっと
Quietly
見つめ合って
Staring at each other
君の気配を
I want to feel
感じていたい
Your presence
乙女の願い
A maiden's wish
踊れや
Dance
今こんなに嬉しくて
Now I'm so happy
踊れほら
Look, dance
こんなに嬉しくて
I'm so happy
気分次第で
Depending on my mood
遠くへ飛びそう
I might fly far away
歌えや
Sing
今こんなに楽しくて
Now I'm having so much fun
歌えほら
Look, sing
こんなに楽しくて
I'm having so much fun
ずっともっと
Forever and more
一緒に
Together
遊びたい
I want to play
気持ちが奏でる
Feelings playing...
桜色ハーモニー
...cherry blossom colored harmony
いろはにほっ
Iroha ni ho-
ぱっとぱっと
Suddenly, suddenly
晴れやかに
Cheerfully
咲かせましょう
Let's make it bloom
花のように
Like a flower
これからも
From now on
君が
I want to
見たい
See you
いろはにほっ
Iroha ni ho-
ぱっとぱっと
Suddenly, suddenly
晴れやかに
Cheerfully
咲かせる思いは
The feelings blooming are
常ならば
If it's always like this
だって
Because
乙女心は
A maiden's heart
風まかせだと
Is left to the wind
呟いてみた
I tried murmuring
乙女心さ
It's a maiden's heart
いろにほへと
Iro ni hoheto
散りたくないの
I don't want to scatter
ハッピーウェディング前ソング
Happy Wedding Song to Be
あれなんかちょっといい感じ？
未来予想図を描いちゃう感じ？
Wait, is this a good vibe?
Like drawing a vision for the future?
客観的に見てお似合いやん
Objectively speaking, we're a good match
趣味とか好きな音楽似てるにゃん
Our hobbies and favorite music are similar
まんざらでもない顔してるにゃん
You're making a face like you don't mind it
あれなんかちょっといい感じ？
未来予想図を描いちゃう感じ？
Wait, is this a good vibe?
Like drawing a vision for the future?
やっぱり出会いって必然的にゃん
Encounters are inevitable after all
運命とか信じるタイプやろ
You're the type to believe in fate, right?
うちが舵持ってあげる
I'll take the helm
愛とか 恋とか そういうの 吹っ飛ばして
Blowing away love and romance and all that
直感で動いてみたらええやん
Just move on intuition
ちょっとだけ冷やかしてみてもいいかな
Can I tease you just a little bit?
キッス！キッス！キッス！キッス！
キッス！キッス！キッス！からの
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! And then...
入籍！入籍！入籍！入籍！
入籍！入籍！入籍！ノリで
Marriage registration! Marriage registration! (x7)
Just for the hell of it
入籍してみたらええやん
君らお似合いやん それハッピーやん
Why not just get married?
You two look good together. That's happy
これから一生ずっと一緒に居るやん速攻
You'll be together for the rest of your lives
婚姻届 役所に届けよう
Let's submit the marriage certificate right away
入籍してみたらええやん
後のことは責任取らんけど
Why not just get married?
I won't take responsibility for what happens later
きっと上手くいくよ
何となくそんな 気がしてるんだ
It'll surely work out
I just have a feeling that it will
あれ本当にちょっといい感じ？
前触れもなく当然にゃん
Wait, is this really a good vibe?
It came naturally without warning
本格的に感じ出してるにゃん
I'm starting to feel it for real
マジで市役所行こうとしてるにゃん
You're really trying to go to the city hall
え、マジで市役所行こうとしてるやん
Wait, you're really trying to go to the city hall
大丈夫？マジ大丈夫？
Are you okay? Seriously?
え、君らがいいならいいやけど、いいの？
Well, if you're okay with it, is it okay?
ほんまにそれで大丈夫？
Is that really okay?
え、ほんまに大丈夫なん？
Wait, is it really okay?
愛とか 恋とか そういうの 吹っ飛ばして
Blowing away love and romance and all that
直感で動いてみたらええやん
Just move on intuition
冷静な判断 今は捨ててさ
Throw away calm judgment for now
キッス！キッス！キッス！キッス！
キッス！キッス！キッス！からの
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! And then...
入籍！入籍！入籍！入籍！
入籍！入籍！入籍！ノリで
Marriage registration! Marriage registration! (x7)
Just for the hell of it
入籍してみたらええやん
君らお似合いやん それハッピーやん
Why not just get married?
You two look good together. That's happy
これから一生ずっと一緒に居るやん速攻
You'll be together for the rest of your lives
ゼクシィ買って 式に備えよう
Let's buy Zexy and prepare for the ceremony
入籍してみたらええやん
多分2年以内に別れると
Why not just get married?
Though I think you'll probably break up within two years
心のどこかで 思っているけど
秘密にしておくね
Somewhere in my heart, I'm thinking that
But I'll keep it a secret
金銭感覚 物の価値観 身体の相性
Financial sense, values, physical compatibility
言えない過去や 消したい過去は
お互いにたくさんあるけれど
Unspeakable pasts or pasts we want to erase
We both have many of them, but
モラハラ ギャンブル 年収と嫁姑問題
Moral harassment, gambling, income and in-law issues
どうしようもない 浮気癖とか
不安はあるけれどさ
Uncontrollable cheating habits and such
There are anxieties, but
ノリで入籍してみたらええやん
君らお似合いやん それハッピーやん
Why not just get married for the hell of it?
You two look good together. That's happy
これから一生ずっと一緒に居るやん速攻
婚姻届 役所に届けよう
You'll be together for the rest of your lives
Let's submit the marriage certificate right away
入籍してみたらええやん
後のことは責任取らんけど
Why not just get married?
I won't take responsibility for what happens later
きっと上手くいくよ
何となくそんな 気がしてるんだ
It'll surely work out
I just have a feeling that it will
入籍してみた ええやん
きっと2年以内に別れるけど
We tried getting married. It's fine
Though we'll surely break up within two years
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ノリで入籍してみたら ええやん ええやん ええやん
イェーイ！
Why not just get married for the hell of it?
It's fine, it's fine, it's fine. Yeah!
おめでとう！ おめでとう！ 結婚おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Congratulations on your marriage!
Happy Wedding!
君が持ってきた漫画くれた 知らない名前の花
The manga you brought gave me
a flower with a name I didn't know
今日はまだ来ないかな 初めての感情 知ってしまった
I wonder if they're coming today
I've learned a new feeling
窓辺飾った絵画 なぞる一人で宇宙を旅して
A painting decorating the windowsill
Tracing it, traveling the universe alone
それだけでいいはずだったのに
That should have been enough, and yet
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I end up holding your hand
孤独を知らないこの街には
In this city that doesn't know loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることは
I probably won't be able to
できないのでしょう
Return ever again
君が手を差し伸べた
You reached out your hand
光で影が生まれる
Light gives birth to shadows
歌って聴かせて
Sing and let me hear
この話の続き
the continuation of this story
連れて行って
Take me away
見たことない星まで
to a star I've never seen
誰の手も声も届かない
No one's hand or voice can reach
高くそびえ立った塔の上
Atop a high, towering tower
飛ばす風船 カモフラージュ
Flying balloons, camouflage
僕は君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want you to smile
満たされない穴は未完成の愛か
Is the unfilled hole an incomplete love?
今は欺いたポーズで
For now, in a deceptive pose
これまでは運命的だったけど
It has been fateful until now, but...
退屈な日々を蹴散らして
Kicking away the boring days
君と二人で
With just the two of us
この街中を
In this town
泳げたら
If we could swim
それはどれだけ素敵なことでしょう？
How wonderful would that be?
出したことないほど
More than I've ever put out
大きな
A loud...
声でやっと君に
...voice finally to you
伝わる
will reach
歪なくらいが
Being a little distorted
きっとちょうどいいよね
is probably just right
世界の端と端を
Connecting the edges of the world
結んで
Together
窓に飾った貝殻なぞって
Tracing the shells decorated on the window
一人の宇宙を旅して
Traveling through my own universe alone
それだけでも不自由ないけど
Even that alone is not inconvenient, but...
僕は選んでみたいの
I want to try choosing
高鳴る心 なぞだらけの空は
A throbbing heart, the sky full of mysteries
安全なループを 今 掻き消して
Erasing the safe loop now
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I end up holding your hand
孤独を知らないこの街には
To this city that knows no loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることは
I probably won't be able to
できないのでしょう
return ever again
いくらでも迷いながら
While getting lost as much as we want
光も影も見に行こう
Let's go see both light and shadow
歌って聴かせて
Sing and let me hear
この話の続き
the continuation of this story
連れて行って
Take me away
見たことない星まで
to a star I've never seen
世界の端と端を
Connecting the edges of the world
結んで
Together
壊れていたのは 世界でしょうか
Was it the world that was broken?
間違っていたのは 世界でしょうか
Was it the world that was wrong?
あなたには朝がやってこない
Morning doesn't come for you
だから あなたの「おはよう」はもう聞けない
So I can't hear your "Good morning" anymore
時が戻れば なんて思いながら
While thinking, "If only time could go back"
私はあなたを こんな檻に閉じ込めてる
I'm locking you up in a cage like this
声が枯れるまで 歌い続ければ
If I keep singing until my voice gives out
きっと 気がついてくれるよね
Surely you'll notice me
またいつか 光の降る街を
Again someday, in the city where light falls
手を繋いで歩きましょう
Let's walk hand in hand
空の青さを忘れるなんて
To forget the blueness of the sky...
全く本当にあなたは馬鹿ね
...you really are a fool
あなたの花が明けるまで
Until Your Flower Dawns
壊れていたのは世界ではなくて
It wasn't the world that was broken
間違っていたのはあなただけれど
It was you who was wrong, but...
嘘で固められた世界でも
Even in a world built on lies
ごめんね あなたに生きててほしいの
I'm sorry, I want you to live
時が戻ればなんて思いながら
While thinking "if only time could turn back"
私はもう少しだけ諦めてる
I've given up just a little bit more
声が枯れるまで歌い続けるのは
Continuing to sing until my voice withers
あなたのためだけじゃない
Isn't just for your sake
またいつか春の空を
Let's walk under the spring sky
二人手をつないで歩きましょう
Holding hands again someday
何も知らないあなたでいいの
It's okay for you to know nothing
私はどこにも行かないから
Because I'm not going anywhere
Lily Lily 君の幸せなんて
Lily, Lily, your happiness...
願ってたあの頃に戻れないんだ
I can't return to those days when I wished for it
知ってるよ どうにもならないことも
I know, even the things that can't be helped
でも嫌いになんてなれなかったよ
But I couldn't come to hate you
またいつか光を歌いながら
Let's walk holding hands again someday
二人手をつないで歩きましょう
Singing of the light
明けない夜はないと教えてくれたこと
That you taught me there's no night that doesn't end
私の手を引いてくれたこと
That you took my hand
あなたを忘れないよ
I won't forget you
Lily Lily 僕本当は君が好きだよ
Lily, Lily, I really love you
Lily Lily 君はどう？
Lily, Lily, how about you?
私もあなたが好きよ
I love you too
ライカ
Leica
一瞬で過ぎてった春も
Spring that passed in an instant
夏も秋も美しくて
Summer and autumn were beautiful too
もうこんな僕はそのまま連れて行って
Just take me away as I am
冬を待つ君の赤いマフラー
Your red scarf waiting for winter
赤くなった頬が可愛くて
Your reddened cheeks were cute
ライカで写した君の顔を思い出した
I remembered your face taken with the Leica
I miss you このまま
I miss you, if only I could
いってしまえたらなんて
Just go like this
最低な僕は歌う君に愛を
The worst me sings love to you
I love you このまま
I love you, if only I could
いってしまえたら僕は
Just go like this
泣いていた君の涙さえ愛おしくて
Even your tears as you cried are precious
舞い散るな
Don't scatter
三秒前に泣き止んだ
You stopped crying three seconds ago
君の長い髪が愛おしくて
Your long hair is precious
もう冬が終わる春が来る
Winter is already ending, spring is coming
きみはいったい...
Who are you exactly...
君は春のように優しかった
You were kind like spring
それはきっと恋だと気づいた
I realized it must be love
夢の中でも君に会えたなら
If only I could see you even in my dreams
なんて言うをー
What would I say?
I miss you このまま行ってしまえたらなんて
I miss you, if only I could just leave like this
青春は青い春を連れ去ってしまう
Youth carries away the blue spring
I love you このまま行ってしまえたら僕は
I love you, if only I could just leave like this, I...
泣いている君を抱きしめてしまいたい今
want to hold you while you're crying right now
わかってるよ
I know
I miss you このまま行ってしまえたらなんて
I miss you, if only I could just leave like this
最低な僕は君を汚していたくて
The worst me wanted to stain you
I love you このまま行ってしまえたら僕は
I love you, if only I could just leave like this, I...
最愛の君に愛を伝えられたなら
If only I could have conveyed my love to my beloved you
サヨナラさ
It's goodbye
はい。というわけで、ここまで見てくれてありがとう！
Okay. So, thank you for watching this far!
最後の曲と重大発表がまだ実は残ってるんですが、
Actually, the final song and a major announcement are still to come,
その前に、グッズの告知を先にしたいと思います！
but before that, I'd like to announce the goods first!
ででーん！
Ta-da!
紫咲シオン活動5周年記念グッズ！いえーい！
Murasaki Shion 5th Anniversary Goods! Yay!
ということで活動記念5周年フルセットはこんな感じになっています。
So, here's the 5th Anniversary Full Set.
一個ずつ丁寧に紹介していくので、最後まで見ていってください。
I'll introduce each item carefully, so please watch until the end.
というわけでですね、まずフルセット購入特典なんですけど、
So then, first is the full set purchase bonus,
え、まずここがもうメインというか、もうでっかい、もうでっかいところなんですけど、
well, first of all, this is the main part, a really huge, huge point,
なんと！今回なんですけど、これ多分、
unbelievably! This time, this is probably...
最初で最後レベルだと思います。
...on a "first and last time" level.
今回フルセット購入した方全員に直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
Everyone who buys the full set this time will get a hand-signed Instax-style bromide card!
直筆サイン入りです、全部！
They're hand-signed, all of them!
数量限定じゃないのは多分なんですけど、最初で最後かなーって思います。
It's not limited in quantity, so I think it's probably the first and last time.
この戦争を俺が止めに来た。
"I've come to stop this war."
というわけで、あのぜひフルセットで購入したら直筆サイン入りチェキ風カードがついてくるので、
So, if you buy the full set, you'll get a hand-signed Instax-style card,
そちらも、あの、数量限定じゃないからあの慌てないでください。
so please don't panic, as it's not limited in quantity.
というわけでですね、やっとグッズを一個目ちゃんと紹介していきたいと思います。
So then, I'd finally like to properly introduce the first item of goods.
まず一個目！キラキラ☆2層アクリルパネル！
First item! Sparkling 2-Layer Acrylic Panel!
ということでキラキラ☆2層アクリルパネル。
So, it's the Sparkling 2-Layer Acrylic Panel.
なんと、キラキラしちゃっているあの層になってるアクリルパネルですね。
It's a layered acrylic panel that's all sparkly.
めっちゃ可愛いイラストをね、Ameもち先生に描いてもらいました。
I had Amemochi-sensei draw this very cute illustration.
めっちゃ可愛いです。あの塩っ子がね、塩っ子足掴んでシオンがゲームしてる感じですね。
It's so cute. It's like Shion is playing a game while a Shiokko is grabbing her foot.
めっちゃ可愛いよねこれ本当に。お部屋にねあのぜひ飾ってほしいなって思います。
Isn't it really cute? I'd really love for you to display it in your room.
今までね、アクリルパネルとかそういうものはあの出したことがなかったので、
I haven't released anything like an acrylic panel before,
今回はですねアクリルパネルにしてみました。キラキラしててとっても可愛いです。
so this time I decided to make one. It's sparkly and very cute.
というわけで、次！
Next!
激カワタンブラー！
Super Cute Tumbler!
はい、こちら皆さん欲しいなーって思ってましたよね。うん絶対思ってたはず。
Yes, you all wanted this, right? I'm sure you did.
もう絶対に思ってた。タンブラー欲しい。
You definitely thought, "I want a tumbler."
最近タンブラー欲しかったんだよねって思ってた。
"I've been wanting a tumbler lately."
シオンも思ってた。いやタンブラー欲しいなーって思ってた。
Shion thought so too. "I want a tumbler."
これめっちゃ可愛くてめっちゃこだわって作ったんですよ。
This is really cute and I put a lot of thought into making it.
そもそもあの中身が見える透明な蓋って書いてあってあの、そう中身が見えるんです、上から。
First off, it has a transparent lid that lets you see inside from above.
で、蓋がシリコンになっててピンク色のシリコンになってて、
The lid is made of pink silicone,
外身があのピンクと薄紫のパステルカラーのグラデーションになってて、
and the body has a pastel pink and light purple gradient,
でこのデザインが何て言うんだろうな、ちょっとぷっくりしたプリントになってる。
and the design is... how should I say, it's a slightly raised print.
こう指で触ると、なんかちょっとだけあのポコっとしてる感じ。本当にもうちょっともう、
When you touch it with your finger, it feels a bit bumpy. Really just a little,
あの1ミリとかもうないレベルのポコって感じのめっちゃ可愛くて、
like, less than a millimeter of bumpiness, but it's really cute,
そうステンレスでできてて、蓋はシリコン...
and it's made of stainless steel, with a silicone lid...
激カワタンブラー
Super Cute Tumbler
これ、めっちゃ可愛いの。見てみて。
This is really cute. Take a look.
めっちゃいいんだよ、本当に。
It's really good, seriously.
もうね、デザインも、もうシオンっぽくて。
The design is so Shion-like.
リボン、この、通常衣装にいつもついてる...
The ribbon is the one that's always on my default outfit...
...あの、胸元のリボン。
...the one at the chest.
で、裏に「Murasaki Shion」ってね...
And on the back, "Murasaki Shion" is written...
...あの、おしゃれなフォントで書いてあります。
...in a stylish font.
めっちゃ可愛いから、これぜひみんな、あの、使ってください。
It's super cute, so please use it, everyone.
お仕事しながらとか、作業しながらとか...
While working, doing chores...
...ゲームしながらとか、飲んでください。
...or playing games, please drink from it.
あのお茶とか入れて。キンキンに冷えたお茶、飲んでください。
Put some tea in it. Drink some ice-cold tea.
というわけで、「激カワタンブラー」です。
Anyway, it's the "Super Cute Tumbler."
これめっちゃいいよね。そう、ずっと作りたかったんだよ。
It's really nice, isn't it? Yeah, I've always wanted to make one.
ショルダーバッグ
Shoulder Bag
次！ショルダーバッグ！
Next! Shoulder bag!
あ、これもね、めっちゃこだわったよ。
Ah, I put a lot of thought into this one too.
マジで、毎回グッズめっちゃ全部こだわってんだけど。
Seriously, I'm picky about all my merch every time.
でも本当に、マジでこだわってて。
But really, I was super particular about this.
まず、この紐がね、紐に「Murasaki Shion」って書いてあるんだよね。
First, "Murasaki Shion" is written on the strap.
このショルダーの紐に。これめっちゃよくて...
On this shoulder strap. This is really great...
...なんか、あの、刺繍みたいになってて。
...it's like embroidery.
ですごいおしゃれなんだよね。
It's very stylish.
で、シンプルな、あの、シンプルだけど...
I aimed for a simple design...
...見る人が見たら分かる、みたいなデザインを目指して作ったから。
...one that those who know will recognize.
あの、表は真っ黒のショルダーバッグなんだけど。
The front is a pitch-black shoulder bag.
このメタルパーツって言ってね、あの、鉄みたいなパーツがついてて。
But it has these metal parts, like iron-like components.
で、これがね、シオンの帽子になってるんだよね。
And these are shaped like Shion's hat.
いや、これもね、見る人が見たら分かるやつだよね。
Yeah, this is another one of those "if you know, you know" things.
で、内側の生地も、こうおしゃれな感じに...
The inner lining also has a stylish feel...
...シンプルな感じにね、なってて。
...it's very simple.
結構使いやすい、マジで使いやすいと思います。デザイン的にも。
It's very practical; I think it's really easy to use.
でですね、タグはですね...
And the tag is...
...あの、Tシャツとか、あの、ブルゾンとかについてたタグと...
...the same one used for the T-shirts and jackets.
...同じタグになっていて。あの、ちょっとシオンブランドっぽくなってるよね。
It feels a bit like a "Shion Brand," right?
あの、お揃いだから。で、可愛くできたかなって思ってます。
Because they match. I think it turned out cute.
シンプルなので、ぜひ外に持ち運んで使ってください。
It's simple, so please take it out and use it.
ショルダーバッグです。
That's the shoulder bag.
キャップ
Cap
次！キャップ！
Next! Cap!
将来的にシオンは、あの、塩っ子のみんなを全身...
In the future, I want to make it so all the Shiokkos...
...あの、シオンが出したグッズで、あの、歩けるように...
...can walk around completely dressed in Shion's merch.
...あの、したいなと思いましたので。キャップを選ばせていただきました。
That's why I chose a cap.
キャップもね、まだ出したことがないグッズなのでね。
Caps are also something I haven't released before.
これもね、結構シンプルな感じで。外で被りやすいようなデザインにしました。
I made it a simple design that's easy to wear outside.
あのね、シオンの「S」にね、あの、帽子がついてて。
There's a hat on the "S" for Shion.
もう、見る人が見たら分かる感じになってて。
Again, it's the kind of thing where if you know, you know.
横にもね、ちょっとだけデザイン入ってて。
There's a bit of design on the side too.
後ろに、あの、タグがついてて。
And a tag on the back.
この金具で、サイズ調整ができるようになってます。
You can adjust the size with this clasp.
金具もね、シルバーにして。あの、シンプルな感じでまとめました。
I made the clasp silver. I kept it all simple.
ぜひ被ってね。
Please wear it!
活動5周年記念フルセット
Activity 5th Anniversary Full Set
はい、そして、このフルセットを購入すると...
And if you buy this full set...
...チェキ風ブロマイドカードにシオンが直筆でサインを書いて...
...I'll hand-sign a cheki-style bromide card...
...えー、みんなの手元に届くという感じです。
...and send it to you.
今回はあの、全員に書くので、あの、慌てないでくださいね。
I'm signing for everyone this time, so don't panic.
でも忘れないでくださいね。
But don't forget, okay?
はい！というわけで、グッズの紹介は以上になります。
Alright! So that concludes the merch introduction.
ここからまだ、一曲と重大発表が残っているので...
We still have one song and a major announcement left...
...最後までちゃんと見てってくださいね。
...so make sure to watch until the end.
はい！というわけで、グッズ告知でした！
Okay! That was the merch announcement!
告知でね、「続きます」と言いましたが...
I said "it continues,"
...何が続くのかですよね！
but I'm sure you're wondering what continues!
なんと！5周年記念に、オリ曲が出ます！
Believe it or not! I'm releasing an original song!
イェーイ！
Yay!
なんとですね、作詞・作曲はHoneyWorksさんです！
And the lyrics and composition are by HoneyWorks!
イェーイ！
Yay!
めちゃめちゃいい曲なので、今から、この後、歌いまーす！
It's a great song, so I'm going to sing it right now!
みんなちゃんと聞いてください。歌いまーす！
Everyone, please listen closely. Here I go!
さあごらんあれ
Now, look at me
シンデレラ・マジック
Cinderella Magic
君のシンデレラ
Your Cinderella
アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un, deux, trois
今宵も
Tonight, again,
始めよう
let's begin.
Shall we dance!
おとぎ話の主人公
The protagonist of a fairy tale
いつも鏡の中で夢見てる
Always dreaming inside the mirror
弱音だらけの私でも
Even though I'm full of complaints,
画面の中では強くありたい
I want to be strong inside the screen.
だけど
But...
強がり　怖がり　寂しがり
Acting tough, being scared, feeling lonely,
弱虫　言われてばかりで
I'm always being called a coward.
思い出す度に震える声
My voice trembles every time I remember.
なんて
Just kidding...
そんなの嘘っぱちだから
that's all a big lie.
信じて
Trust me,
私だけをみて
and look only at me.
反撃開始のドレスを着て
Wearing a dress to start the counterattack,
魔法
before the magic
解ける前に
wears off.
さあごらんあれ
Now, look at me
君のシンデレラ
Your Cinderella
アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un, deux, trois
ガラスの靴履いて
Wearing glass slippers,
可愛く映ってます！
looking cute on screen!
誇らしげに踊って見せよう
I'll show you my dance with pride.
これが
This is
Ah ✨✨✨
高らかに
Louder,
響かせ
let it ring out.
「所詮は」だなんて
"After all," you say,
分かったふりして口から出まかせで
pretending to know, just talking nonsense.
「ホントは」だなんて
"In truth," you say,
甘過ぎ軽口言いたくないんだって
I don't want to hear such sweet, cheap talk.
ノイズ無視して全部笑い飛ばして
Ignoring the noise, laughing it all away,
不安拭って立ち止まるな
wipe away the anxiety and don't stop!
そらさないで
Don't look away,
強くいさせて
let me stay strong.
アン・ドゥ・トロワ！
One, two, three!
0時を回っても
Even after the clock strikes midnight,
逃がさずに戦っているの
I'm fighting without letting go.
気高く華麗に
Nobly and elegantly,
舞い上がる
I'll soar high!
泣いてる暇なんかない
There's no time for crying!
「タラレバ」なんかじゃなく
Not just "ifs" and "buts,"
「これから」を生きたいの
I want to live for "what's next."
反撃開始のドレスを着て
Wearing the dress of the counterattack,
魔法が解ける前に
before the magic wears off.
さあご覧あれ
Now, behold,
君のシンデレラ
your Cinderella.
アン・ドゥ・トロワ！
One, two, three!
ガラスの靴履いて
Wearing the glass slippers,
可愛く映ってますか？
do I look cute on screen?
誇らしげに
With pride,
踊って見せよう
I'll show you my dance.
これが私なんだ
This is who I am.
Shall We Dance!
Ah ✨✨✨
誇らしげに
With pride...
もっと
More...
Shall we...
ね？
...right?
あっ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a second!
このあと24時からオリジナル曲「シンデレラ・マジック」の
Starting from 24:00 tonight, the streaming for my original song "Cinderella Magic"...
ストリーミング配信が始まるから、
...will begin,
みんなちゃんとチェックしてねー！
so make sure to check it out, everyone!
紫咲シオン 5th Anniversary LIVE Thank you
Murasaki Shion 5th Anniversary LIVE Thank you